A Guide to the Rockefeller Family Public Relations Department papers, Series 13 FA1193
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Family Public Relations Department papers, Series 13
1900, 1906, 1910-1915, 1927, 1931, 1937, 1940, 1945, 1948-1987, 1989
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison), 1906-1978
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman
Rockefeller, David
FA1193
14.11 Cubic Feet 28 legal size record storage boxes 1 1/2 legal size record storage box 1 16x20 oversized record storage box
Arrangement
The material remains in original order.
Scope and Contents
Type of records include: Reports, publications, newspaper articles, correspondence, reprints, architectural drawings and maps, and photographs
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Other Finding Aids
For other available Rockefeller Family public relations department papers please see:
FA789A Rockefeller Family Public Relations Department papers, Series 1-9
FA789 Rockefeller Family Public Relations Department papers, Series 10-12
FA329 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Public Relations, Series T
- Smith, Fred, "LSR" Book, Part 1 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Smith, Fred, "LSR" Book, Part 2 (Box 1, Folder 3-6)
- Smith, M. Frederick, "Notes on the Life and Times of John D. Rockefeller's 3rd Grandson" (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Berger, Albert I., "My Father's House at Pocantico Hills, Kykuit and the Business Education of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.", 1985 February (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
- Castro, Nash, Executive Director, Palisades Interstate Park Commission, Remarks, 1989 June 15 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- "A Walker's Guide to The Old Croton Aqueduct" (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Shapiro, Isaac and Arthur William Rashap, "Social Considerations in Institutional Investment Management, A Report for the Rockefeller Family", 1972 January (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Institutional Investor, 1981 May (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Dalrymple, Martha, "The AIA Story, Two Decades of International Cooperation", 1968 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Holm, Bill and Bill Reid, "Indian Art of the Northwest Coast, A Dialogue on Craftsmanship and Aesthetics", 1975 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Frost, Dick, "The Rockefeller Encyclopedia, 100 Years of Marriages & Births In The Eight Branches of the John & William Rockefeller Clans", 1987 (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
- "Master Plan and Draft Environmental Impact Statement, Proposed State Park, Rockefeller Property, Pocantico Hills", 1982 October 1 (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
- "Master Plan and Draft Environmental Impact Statement, Proposed State Park, Rockefeller Property, Pocantico Hills", 1982 October 1 (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
- Malik, Charles, "Will the Future Redeem the Past?", 1960 June 11 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Rockefeller, Nelson A., Articles on Winning Governor, 1958, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Rockwood Hall (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Pocantico Hills Estate, Taxes, etc., 1980, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Rockefeller Family & Associates, Reports on Family Financial Entities, 1984, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Weekend Retreat of the 5600 Staff, Briefing Materials, 1985 February 1-3 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Weekend Retreat of the 5600 Staff, Summary, 1985 February 1-3 (Box 5, Folder 28-29)
- Hitchcock, Elizabeth French, Memorial Service, 1976 February 17 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Barton, Robert S., Memorial Service, 1981 January 21 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Mauze, Jean, Memorial Service, 1974 April 27 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Kykuit: A National Historic Landmark, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., "The Case for a Simpler Life-Style", Reprint, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Rockefeller, David, "DR: Retirement Week, 1981", 1981 April (Box 6, Folder 35)
- "Sea Star", Brochure, 1976 April 19 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Rockefeller, Jay, Articles from the Charleston Daily Mail, 1977 January 17 (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Rockefeller, Jay, Articles from the Charleston Gazette, 1981 January 20 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Moscow, Alvin, "The Rockefeller Inheritance" (Box 6, Folder 39-41)
- Moscow, Alvin, "The Rockefeller Inheritance", Chapter 21 and Edits, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Moscow, Alvin, Correspondence, 1972, 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 43-44)
- Moscow, Alvin, "The Rockefeller Inheritance", Chapters 15 & 16, David Rockefeller, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 45-46)
- Moscow, Alvin, "The Rockefeller Inheritance", Chapter 13, Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Moscow, Alvin, "The Rockefeller Inheritance", Chapter 18, Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 47)
- Moscow, Alvin, "The Rockefeller Inheritance", Chapter 12, Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 49)
- Moscow, Alvin, "The Rockefeller Inheritance", Chapter 19, Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 50)
- CBS Documentary, 1962, 1972-1974 (Box 8, Folder 51)
- CBS Documentary, 1973 December 28, 1972-1974 (Box 8, Folder 52-53)
- CBS Documentary, Transcripts, 1973 December 28 (Box 8, Folder 54)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Accident News Coverage, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 55-57)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, New York City Newspapers, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 58)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Accident News Coverage, West Virginia, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 59)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Accident News Coverage, Westchester Newspapers, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 60)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Memorial Service, 1978 July 13 (Box 9, Folder 61)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Memorial Services, John D. Rockefeller IV, Advance Copies of Remarks Delivered, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 62)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Memorial Book, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 63)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Williamsburg Papers, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 64)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Foreign Newspapers, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 65)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Memorial Service, Newspapers, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 66)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Editorials, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 67)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Paid Death Notices, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 68)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Time, 1978 July 24 (Box 10, Folder 69)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Main Stories, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 70)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Newsweek, 1978 July 24 (Box 10, Folder 71)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Will, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 72)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Sidebars, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 73)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Miscellaneous Correspondence, Messages, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 74)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Newspaper Clippings, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 75)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Will, Press Release, 1978 July 20 (Box 10, Folder 76)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Death, Family Summary, Drafts, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 77)
- Hanks, Nancy, Memorial, 1983 January 18 (Box 10, Folder 78)
- Hanks, Nancy, Obituaries, 1983 January (Box 10, Folder 79)
- Hanks, Nancy, Tribute, Partners for Livable Places Brochure, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 80)
- Hanks, Nancy, Memorial Service, Thank You Letters by Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1983 January (Box 10, Folder 81)
- Hanks, Nancy, Memorial Service, 1983 January 18 (Box 10, Folder 82)
- Hanks, Nancy, Obituaries, Press Release, Memorial Service, and News Clippings, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 83)
- Hanks, Nancy, 1973-1974, 1978-1980, 19892-1983 (Box 10, Folder 84)
- Hanks, Nancy, George D. Taylor, Jr.'s Thank You Letters, 1983 January 31 (Box 11, Folder 85)
- Hanks, Nancy, George D. Taylor, Jr.'s Thank You Letters, 1983 January 31; 2017:FA1193:001; 5" floppy disk
  Conditions Governing Access
  Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
- Rockefeller, Winthrop, 1967, 1969, 1971-1974 (Box 11, Folder 86)
- Rockefeller, Winthrop, Will, Draft, 1973 February 22 (Box 11, Folder 87)
- Rockefeller, Winthrop, Editorial Remarks After Death, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 88)
- Rockefeller, Winthrop, Memorial Book, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 89)
- Rockefeller, Winthrop, Arkansas Gazette, 1973 February 23 & March 5 (Box 11, Folder 90)
- Rockefeller, Winthrop, Death, Clippings and Drafts, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 91)
- Rockefeller, Winthrop, Resolutions, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 92)
- Rockefeller, Winthrop, Memorial Distribution List, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 93)
- Rockefeller, Winthrop, Hospital Clippings, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 94)
- Rockefeller, Winthrop, Hospital Clippings, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 95-96)
- Winrock Farms Data, 1976, 1978-1979 (Box 12, Folder 97)
- Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Folk Art Collection, 1964 February (Box 12, Folder 98)
- Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Memorial Window, 1964 October (Box 12, Folder 99)
- The Agricultural Development Council, Inc., 1964 January (Box 12, Folder 100)
- American Conservation Association, 1963 October (Box 12, Folder 101)
- Arkansas Arts Center, 1963 March (Box 12, Folder 102)
- Arkansas Industrial Development Commission, 1963 March (Box 12, Folder 103)
- Asia Society, 1963 November (Box 12, Folder 104)
- Caneel Bay Plantation, 1963 July (Box 12, Folder 105)
- Carter's Grove, 1964 April (Box 12, Folder 106)
- The Chase Manhattan Bank, 1963 May (Box 12, Folder 107)
- Chile Rural Education Project of the RBF, 1964 March (Box 12, Folder 108)
- Citizens Committee for the Outdoor Recreation Review Commission Report (ORRRC), 1963 February (Box 12, Folder 109)
- The Cloisters, 1963 June (Box 12, Folder 110)
- Colonial Williamsburg, 1963 August, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 111)
- Downtown-Lower Manhattan Association (DLMA), 1962 September (Box 12, Folder 112)
- Educational Broadcasting Corporation, 1962 July (Box 12, Folder 113)
- Educational Broadcasting Corporation, Revised, 1964 August (Box 12, Folder 114)
- Estate Good Hope, 1964 September (Box 12, Folder 115)
- Ettinger Program for Creative Writing, 1963 November (Box 12, Folder 116)
- Executive Mansion, 1964 August (Box 12, Folder 117)
- Flight Safety Foundation, Inc., 1948-1953, 1955, 1959, 1961-1963, 1967, 1969, 1971, 1973-1975, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 118)
- General Education Board, 1962 August (Box 12, Folder 119)
- IBEC Research Institute, 1963 April (Box 12, Folder 120)
- International House, New York, 1963 May (Box 12, Folder 121)
- Interracial Council for Business Opportunity, 1964 September (Box 12, Folder 122)
- International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC), 1962 July (Box 12, Folder 123)
- Asia Society, 1963 August (Box 12, Folder 124)
- Japanese Tea House, 1964 May (Box 12, Folder 125)
- The JDR 3rd Fund, 1963 October (Box 12, Folder 126)
- John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Memorial Window, 1964 November (Box 12, Folder 127)
- Kettering Laboratory, 1964 May (Box 12, Folder 128)
- Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, 1962 September (Box 12, Folder 129)
- Little Dix Bay Resort, 1963 December (Box 12, Folder 130)
- The Magsaysay Award, 1963 September (Box 12, Folder 131)
- Morningside Heights, Inc., 1963 February (Box 12, Folder 132)
- Museum of Automobiles, 1964 October (Box 12, Folder 133)
- Museum of Modern Art, Revised, 1964 June (Box 12, Folder 134)
- Museum of Primitive Art, 1963 January (Box 12, Folder 135)
- New York State Theater at Lincoln Center, 1964 April (Box 12, Folder 136)
- New York World's Fair, 1964-1965, 1962 November (Box 12, Folder 137)
- Outdoor Recreation Resource Review Commission (ORRRC), 1962 August (Box 12, Folder 138)
- Pacific Air Commerce Center, Inc., 1964 February (Box 12, Folder 139)
- Performing Arts Panel, 1964 March (Box 12, Folder 140)
- Pocantico Hills, 1964 July, 1976 March (Box 12, Folder 141)
- Population Council, 1963 January (Box 12, Folder 142)
- Radio City Music Hall, 1964 January (Box 12, Folder 143)
- Rockefeller Center, 1962 December (Box 12, Folder 144)
- Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1963 July (Box 12, Folder 145)
- Rockefeller Foundation, 1963 April (Box 12, Folder 146)
- Rock & Co., 1975, 1978-1980, 1983, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 147)
- Rock & Co., 1975, 1978-1980, 1983, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 147A)
  Restricteds-Confidential material
- Rockefeller Institute, 1963 March (Box 13, Folder 148)
- Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1962 November (Box 13, Folder 149)
- Sleepy Hollow Restorations, Inc., 1963, 1980-1981, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 150)
- Sealantic Fund, Inc., 1962 December (Box 13, Folder 151)
- Theological Fellowship Programs, 1964 July (Box 13, Folder 152)
- United Negro College Fund, 1963 August (Box 13, Folder 153)
- Virgin Island National Park, 1962 September (Box 13, Folder 154)
- Winrock Farms, 1963 September (Box 13, Folder 155)
- International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC), 1955, 1959, 1961, 1963, 1972, 1974-1975, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 156)
- Osborn, Fairfield, Obituary, President of New York Zoological Society, 1949, 1969, 1972, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 157)
- Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI), Brochure and Background Materials, 1980, 1931, 1940, 1945, 1948-1950, 1952, 1954-1956, 1967, 1970, 1973, 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 158-159)
- Kennan, George F., Speeches and Related Material, 1977, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 160)
- Kykuit Guest House, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 161)
- Kykuit, The Japanese House, Snyder Material and Emperor Visit, 1975, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 162)
- Mid-City Community Hypertension and Cardiac Emergency Service, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 163)
- Michigan Hill, Department of Environmental Conservation, 1977, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 164)
- Roberts, Sam & Mike Kramer, Nelson A. Rockefeller Biography, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 165)
- Ottinger, Richard L., Solar Energy File, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 166)
- "Open Skies", W. W. Rostow, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 167)
- Partners, 1982-1983 (Box 14, Folder 168)
- Palisades Interstate Park Commission (PIPC), 1960, 1976, 1978, 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 169)
- Winrock Farms Advertisement, 1976, 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 170)
- Whyte, William, Urban Planning Projects Articles, 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 171)
- Whyte, William, Articles, 1974, 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 172)
- Sotheby Parke Bernet Sale, Estate of Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 173)
- TV Newscast, WNEW, David Rockefeller's Political Contributions, 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 174)
- The Nelson Rockefeller Collection, Inc. Catalog, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 175)
- The Real Paper, Background Material, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 176)
- Rockefeller, Margaretta F., "20 Questions", 1980 (Box 15, Folder 177)
- Ford, Gerald, Visit to Pocantico Hills, Newspaper Clippings, 1976 November (Box 15, Folder 178)
- Rockefeller, Nelson A., Clippings Book, Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 15, Folder 179)
- Distributions, Directory, and Newspaper Clippings, 1974-1976 (Box 15, Folder 180)
- Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, Life Magazine Article, Draft, 1979-1980 (Box 15, Folder 181)
- Pocantico Hills Articles, 1976, 1979-1982 (Box 15, Folder 182)
- Lord, Winston, Council on Foreign Relations, Inc., Henry Kissinger Membership, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 183)
- Valley News, 1983 January 10-14 (Box 15, Folder 184)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Biography, 1982 June (Box 15, Folder 185)
- SUNY Fredonia, Michael C. Rockefeller Plaque, 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 186)
- Gilley Museum, Background Material, Steven Rockefeller, 1980-1981 (Box 15, Folder 187)
- State Visit by Emperor Hirohito to New York, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 188)
- "Rockefeller Family and the Blacks", 1969 August (Box 15, Folder 189)
- "Assistant to the President, A Day with Joe Canzeri", J. D. Solomon, 1981 November 8 (Box 15, Folder 190)
- Beter, Peter, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 191)
- Leamer, Laurance, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 192)
- "The Rockefellers: An American Dynasty", Reviews, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 193)
- O'Neill, Peter, Term Paper on the New Republican Philosophy and George Bush, 1971-1974, 1978-1981 (Box 16, Folder 194)
- Scrivner, Robert W., Memorial Service, 1984 May 16 (Box 16, Folder 195)
- The Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Garden, A Meeting of East and West (Box 16, Folder 196)
- "For Pocantico Hills, a Luxury Project, Builder Proposes 197 Homes Near The Rockefellers", 1983 December 18 (Box 16, Folder 197)
- Jordon Pond House, Articles, 1982 June (Box 16, Folder 198)
- Rockefeller Center, 50th Anniversary, Articles, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 199)
- Articles, Rockefellers, National Parks, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 200)
- Rockefeller State Park, Rockwood Hall, Articles, 1969, 1976, 1978-1979, 1981-1983 (Box 16, Folder 201)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Eastern Airlines, Election to the Board of Directors, 1974 August 27, 1969, 1974, 1981, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 202)
- Cancer Reference Materials, 1900, 1906, 1910, 1912-1913, 1927, 1973, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 203)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC), Paul H. Shakanai Correspondence, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 204)
- "Random Reminiscences of Men and Events", John D. Rockefeller, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 205)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., "Random Reminiscences of Men & Events", Business Rights and Permissions, Audio Cassette, 1983-1985 (Box 17, Folder 206-207)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Research Material, Miscellaneous Quotes and Clips, 1910, 1913, 1937, 1952-1953, 1957-1961, 1964-1967, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 208)
- Woodstock, Vermont, Materials, 1976-1977, 1979, 1981-1984 (Box 17, Folder 209)
- "'Perfection'--At a Price', Robert W. Stock, 1976 December 26 (Box 17, Folder 210)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Grand Teton Lodge Company, Wyoming, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 211)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., JY Ranch, 1968, 1974-1979, 1981, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 212)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Caribair, 1972-1974 (Box 18, Folder 213)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Animal Medical Center, Reference Material, 1984-1985 (Box 18, Folder 214)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Carlisle Humelsine Letter, Retirement, 1985 August (Box 18, Folder 215)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Flight Safety Foundation, Inc., Background Materials, 1948-1949, 1961, 1965, 1971, 1973-1974, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 216)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Property Controversies, 1958-1959, 1982, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 217)
- Estate Fountain River, Sale, 1971-1973, 1979-1980, 1982, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 218)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Clippings on Estate Fountain River, 1979-1980, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 219)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), Background Material, 1983-1984 (Box 18, Folder 220)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) Professorship, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 221)
- "Art Objects of the Mauna Kea Hotel", Comment Request & Copy of Book, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 222)
- "The Mission Called 66", Conrad L. Wirth, 1966 July (Box 18, Folder 223)
- Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission (ORRRC), Background and Current Material, 1962, 1983-1985 (Box 18, Folder 224)
- Conservation: Chronology & Other Research Materials, 1806-1986, 1966 August 17 (Box 19, Folder 225)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Eastern Airlines, Stock Exchange, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 226)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Alcoholism Project, 1982-1983 (Box 19, Folder 227)
- Schorder, Edward A., Sermon, Woodstock, VT, 1975 July 6 (Box 19, Folder 228)
- Schorder, Edward A., Sermon, Woodstock, VT, 1975 July 6; 2017:FA1193:002; Audio cassette, 1975 July 6, Rev "Ted" Schroder
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Venture Capital, Interests, 1959, 1961, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 229)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., General Motors' Award for Cancer Philanthropy, 1979, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 230)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Conservation, Remarks by Other Lecturers, 1962-1963 (Box 19, Folder 231)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Memorial, Remarks by Other Lecturers, Cancer Research, 1954-1955, 1959, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 232)
- Rockefeller, David, "Free Trade In Ideas", 1978 January 19 (Box 19, Folder 233)
- Rockefeller, David, Speech, Chamber of Commerce in the U. S., The Challenge for Puerto Rico, Regaining Pre-Recession Momentum, 1978 April 27 (Box 19, Folder 234)
- Rockefeller, David, Speech, "Culture and the Corporation: An Update", 1978 June 27 (Box 19, Folder 235)
- Rockefeller, David, Speech, Interstate North Building, Groundbreaking, 1978 September 12, 1978-1979, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 236)
- Rockefeller, David, Speech, Renaissance Center Ceremony, 1978 September 22 (Box 19, Folder 237)
- Rockefeller, David, Speech, "The Expansion of Foreign Banks in New York City: Welcome to the Club", 1978 October 4 (Box 19, Folder 238)
- Rockefeller, David, Speech, "The Challenge for the Banking Industry: A Call for Unity", 1978 October 23 (Box 19, Folder 239)
- Rockefeller, David, Speech, "Getting Things Done", 1978 October 27 (Box 19, Folder 240)
- Rockefeller, David, Speech, "A Banker's View of the World Economy", 1978 November 22 (Box 19, Folder 241)
- Rockefeller, David, Speech, "The World Economy: Problems and Prospects", 1978 November 24 (Box 19, Folder 242)
- Rockefeller, David, Speech, "Meeting the World's Food Challenge: The American Farmer at Center Stage", 1978 December 15 (Box 19, Folder 243)
- Rockefeller, David, Speech, "Business Speaks--Does Anybody Listen?", 1979 November 28 (Box 19, Folder 244)
- Rockefeller, David, "In Pursuit of a Consistent Foreign Policy", 1980 April 10 (Box 19, Folder 245)
- Rockefeller, David, Speeches, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 246)
- Rockefeller, David, Speeches, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 247)
- Rockefeller, David, "Interview with David Rockefeller", Cornell University, Executive Magazine, 1981 Fall (Box 20, Folder 248)
- Rockefeller, David, Proposed State Park, Pocantico Hills, 1979, 1981-1982 (Box 20, Folder 249)
- Highman, Charles, "Trading with the Enemy: An Expose of the Nazi-American Money Plot, 1933-1949", 1982-1983 (Box 20, Folder 250)
- Rockefeller, John D., IV, Governor's Conference on Libraries, 1978 October 12 (Box 20, Folder 251)
- The Joint Property of the Rockefeller Brothers, 1967, 1978, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 252-253)
- Kykuit, Pamphlet, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 254-255)
- Kykuit, Art, 1910-1911, 1913-1915, 1953, 1960, 1962, 1970, 1978-1980 (Box 21, Folder 256)
- Kykuit, Filming, 1979-1980 (Box 21, Folder 257)
- "Coming to Our Senses, The Significance of the Arts in American Education", American Council for the Arts in Education, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 258)
- Rockefeller, Nelson A., "The Future of Federalism", 1974 (Box 21, Folder 259)
- The Martha Baird Rockefeller Fund for Music, Inc., 1973-1977, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 260)
- Recollections of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in Williamsburg, 1926-1960, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 261)
- "New Vistas to the Past", the Colonial Williamsburg Foundation, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 262)
- Butcher, Willard C., "Capital Formation and Individual Freedom: A Time to Cry "Wolf", 1975 February 20 (Box 21, Folder 263)
- Rockefeller Family Fund, Report for 1968 & 1969, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 264)
- Twentieth-Century Art From the Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller Collection, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 265)
- Lee, Sherman E., "Asian Art, Selections from the Collection of Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, 3rd", 1970 (Box 22, Folder 266)
- Medeja, Stanley S., "All Arts for Every Child", 1973 (Box 22, Folder 267)
- The JDR 3rd Fund and Asia, 1963-1975, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 268)
- The JDR 3rd Fund Report, 1971, 1973-1976, 1978-1979 (Box 22, Folder 269-270)
- The Edna McConnell Clark Foundation, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 271)
- The Museum of Modern Art, Reports, 1976, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 272)
- International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC), Annual Report, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 273)
- Rockefeller, Laurance S., Remarks, Dedication of the Rockefeller State Park Perserve, 1986 May 2 (Box 22, Folder 274)